You now know about linear regression with multiple variables.
你现在了解了多变量的线性回归
(字幕整理：中国海洋大学 黄海广,haiguang2000@qq.com )
In this video, I wanna tell
在本段视频中 我想告诉你
you a bit about the choice
一些用来
of features that you have and
选择特征的方法以及
how you can get different learning
如何得到不同的学习算法
algorithm, sometimes very powerful
当选择了合适的特征后
ones by choosing appropriate features.
这些算法往往是非常有效的
And in particular I also want
另外 我也想
to tell you about polynomial regression allows
给你们讲一讲多项式回归
you to use the machinery of
它使得你们能够使用
linear regression to fit very
线性回归的方法来拟合
complicated, even very non-linear functions.
非常复杂的函数 甚至是非线性函数
Let's take the example of predicting the price of the house.
以预测房价为例
Suppose you have two features,
假设你有两个特征
the frontage of house and the depth of the house.
分别是房子临街的宽度和垂直宽度
So, here's the picture of the house we're trying to sell.
这就是我们想要卖出的房子的图片
So, the frontage is
临街宽度
defined as this distance
被定义为这个距离
is basically the width
其实就是它的宽度
or the length of
或者说是
how wide your lot
你拥有的土地的宽度
is if this that you
如果这块地都是你的的话
own, and the depth
而这所房子的
of the house is how
纵向深度就是
deep your property is, so
你的房子的深度
there's a frontage, there's a depth.
这是正面的宽度 这是深度
called frontage and depth.
我们称之为临街宽度和纵深
You might build a linear regression
你可能会 像这样 建立一个
model like this where frontage
线性回归模型 其中临街宽度
is your first feature x1 and
是你的第一个特征x1
and depth is your second
纵深是你的第二个
feature x2, but when you're
特征x2 但当我们在
applying linear regression, you don't
运用线性回归时
necessarily have to use
你不一定非要直接用
just the features x1 and x2 that you're given.
给出的 x1 和 x2 作为特征
What you can do is actually create new features by yourself.
其实你可以自己创造新的特征
So, if I want to predict
因此 如果我要预测
the price of a house, what I
房子的价格
might do instead is decide
我真正要需做的 也许是
that what really determines
确定真正能够决定
the size of the house is
我房子大小 或者说我土地大小
the area or the land area that I own.
的因素是什么
So, I might create a new feature.
因此 我可能会创造一个新的特征
I'm just gonna call this feature
我称之为
x which is frontage, times depth.
x 它是临街宽度与纵深的乘积
This is a multiplication symbol.
这是一个乘法符号
It's a frontage x depth because
它是临街宽度与纵深的乘积
this is the land area
这得到的就是我拥有的土地的面积
that I own and I might
然后 我可以把
then select my hypothesis
假设选择为
as that using just
使其只使用
one feature which is my
一个特征 也就是我的
land area, right?
土地的面积 对吧？
Because the area of a
由于矩形面积的
rectangle is you know,
计算方法是
the product of the length
矩形长和宽相乘
of the size So, depending
因此 这取决于
on what insight you might have
你从什么样的角度
into a particular problem, rather than
去审视一个特定的问题 而不是
just taking the features [xx]
只是直接去使用临街宽度和纵深
that we happen to have started
这两个我们只是碰巧在开始时
off with, sometimes by defining
使用的特征 有时 通过定义
new features you might actually get a better model.
新的特征 你确实会得到一个更好的模型
Closely related to the
与选择特征的想法
idea of choosing your features
密切相关的一个概念
is this idea called polynomial regression.
被称为多项式回归(polynomial regression)
Let's say you have a housing price data set that looks like this.
比方说 你有这样一个住房价格的数据集
Then there are a few different models you might fit to this.
为了拟合它 可能会有多个不同的模型供选择
One thing you could do is fit a quadratic model like this.
其中一个你可以选择的是像这样的二次模型
It doesn't look like a straight line fits this data very well.
因为直线似乎并不能很好地拟合这些数据
So maybe you want to fit
因此 也许你会想到
a quadratic model like this
用这样的二次模型去拟合数据
where you think the size, where
你可能会考量
you think the price is a quadratic
是关于价格的一个二次函数
function and maybe that'll
也许这样做
give you, you know, a fit
会给你一个
to the data that looks like that.
像这样的拟合结果
But then you may decide that your
但是 然后你可能会觉得
quadratic model doesn't make sense
二次函数的模型并不好用
because of a quadratic function, eventually
因为 一个二次函数最终
this function comes back down
会降回来
and well, we don't think housing
而我们并不认为
prices should go down when the size goes up too high.
房子的价格在高到一定程度后 会下降回来
So then maybe we might
因此 也许我们会
choose a different polynomial model
选择一个不同的多项式模型
and choose to use instead a
并转而选择使用一个
cubic function, and where
三次函数 在这里
we have now a third-order term
现在我们有了一个三次的式子
and we fit that, maybe
我们用它进行拟合
we get this sort of
我们可能得到这样的模型
model, and maybe the
也许这条绿色的线
green line is a somewhat better fit
对这个数据集拟合得更好
to the data cause it doesn't eventually come back down.
因为它不会在最后下降回来
So how do we actually fit a model like this to our data?
那么 我们到底应该如何将模型与我们的数据进行拟合呢？
Using the machinery of multivariant
使用多元
linear regression, we can
线性回归的方法 我们可以
do this with a pretty simple modification to our algorithm.
通过将我们的算法做一个非常简单的修改来实现它
The form of the hypothesis we,
按照我们以前假设的形式
we know how the fit
我们知道如何对
looks like this, where we say
这样的模型进行拟合 其中
H of x is theta zero
?θ(x) 等于 θ0
plus theta one x one plus x two theta X3.
+θ1×x1 + θ2×x2 + θ3×x3
And if we want to
那么 如果我们想
fit this cubic model that
拟合这个三次模型
I have boxed in green,
就是我用绿色方框框起来的这个
what we're saying is that
现在我们讨论的是
to predict the price of a
为了预测一栋房子的价格
house, it's theta 0 plus theta
我们用 θ0 加 θ1
1 times the size of the house
乘以房子的面积
plus theta 2 times the square size of the house.
加上 θ2 乘以房子面积的平方
So this term is equal to that term.
因此 这个式子与那个式子是相等的
And then plus theta 3
然后再加 θ3
times the cube of the
乘以
size of the house raises that third term.
房子面积的立方
In order to map these
为了将这两个定义
two definitions to each other,
互相对应起来
well, the natural way
为了做到这一点
to do that is to set
我们自然想到了
the first feature x one to
将 x1 特征设为
be the size of the house, and
房子的面积
set the second feature x two
将第二个特征 x2 设为
to be the square of the size
房屋面积的平方
of the house, and set the third feature x three to
将第三个特征 x3 设为
be the cube of the size of the house.
房子面积的立方
And, just by choosing my
那么 仅仅通过将
three features this way and
这三个特征这样设置
applying the machinery of linear
然后再应用线性回归的方法
regression, I can fit this
我就可以拟合
model and end up with
这个模型 并最终
a cubic fit to my data.
将一个三次函数拟合到我的数据上
I just want to point out one
我还想再说一件事
more thing, which is that
那就是
if you choose your features
如果你像这样选择特征
like this, then feature scaling
那么特征的归一化
becomes increasingly important.
就变得更重要了
So if the size of the
因此 如果
house ranges from one to
房子的大小范围在
a thousand, so, you know,
1到1000之间 那么
from one to a thousand square
比如说
feet, say, then the size
从1到1000平方尺 那么
squared of the house will
房子面积的平方
range from one to one
的范围就是
million, the square of
一到一百万 也就是
a thousand, and your third
1000的平方 而你的第三个特征
feature x cubed, excuse me
x的立方 抱歉
you, your third feature x
你的第三个特征 x3
three, which is the size
它是房子面积的
cubed of the house, will range
立方 范围会扩大到
from one two ten to
1到10的9次方
the nine, and so these
因此
three features take on very
这三个特征的范围
different ranges of values, and
有很大的不同
it's important to apply feature
因此 如果你使用梯度下降法
scaling if you're using gradient
应用特征值的归一化是非常重要的
descent to get them into
这样才能将他们的
comparable ranges of values.
值的范围变得具有可比性
Finally, here's one last example
最后 这里是最后一个例子
of how you really have
关于如何使你
broad choices in the features you use.
真正选择出要使用的特征
Earlier we talked about how a
此前我们谈到
quadratic model like this might
一个像这样的二次模型
not be ideal because, you know,
并不是理想的 因为 你知道
maybe a quadratic model fits the
也许一个二次模型能很好地拟合
data okay, but the quadratic
这个数据 但二次
function goes back down
函数最后会下降
and we really don't want, right,
这是我们不希望的
housing prices that go down,
就是住房价格往下走
to predict that, as the size of housing freezes.
像预测的那样 出现房价的下降
But rather than going to
但是 除了转而
a cubic model there, you
建立一个三次模型以外
have, maybe, other choices of
你也许有其他的选择
features and there are many possible choices.
特征的方法 这里有很多可能的选项
But just to give you another
但是给你另外一个
example of a reasonable
合理的选择的例子
choice, another reasonable choice
另一种合理的选择
might be to say that the
可能是这样的
price of a house is theta
一套房子的价格是
zero plus theta one times
θ0 加 θ1 乘以
the size, and then plus theta
房子的面积 然后
two times the square root of the size, right?
加 θ2 乘以房子面积的平方根 可以吧？
So the square root function is
平方根函数是
this sort of function, and maybe
这样的一种函数
there will be some value of theta
也许θ1 θ2 θ3
one, theta two, theta three, that
中会有一些值
will let you take this model
会捕捉到这个模型
and, for the curve that looks
从而使得这个曲线看起来
like that, and, you know,
是这样的
goes up, but sort of flattens
趋势是上升的 但慢慢变得
out a bit and doesn't ever
平缓一些 而且永远不会
come back down.
下降回来
And, so, by having insight into, in
因此 通过深入地研究
this case, the shape of a
在这里我们研究了平方根
square root function, and, into
函数的形状 并且
the shape of the data, by choosing
更深入地了解了选择不同特征时数据的形状
different features, you can sometimes get better models.
有时可以得到更好的模型
In this video, we talked about polynomial regression.
在这段视频中 我们探讨了多项式回归
That is, how to fit a
也就是 如何将一个
polynomial, like a quadratic function,
多项式 如一个二次函数
or a cubic function, to your data.
或一个三次函数拟合到你的数据上
Was also throw out this idea,
除了这个方面
that you have a choice in what
我们还讨论了
features to use, such as
在使用特征时的选择性
that instead of using
例如 我们不使用
the frontish and the depth
房屋的临街宽度和纵深
of the house, maybe, you can
也许 你可以
multiply them together to get
把它们乘在一起 从而得到
a feature that captures the land area of a house.
房子的土地面积这个特征
In case this seems a little
实际上 这似乎有点
bit bewildering, that with all
难以抉择 这里有这么多
these different feature choices, so how do I decide what features to use.
不同的特征选择 我该如何决定使用什么特征呢
Later in this class, we'll talk
在之后的课程中 我们将
about some algorithms were automatically
探讨一些算法 它们能够
choosing what features are used,
自动选择要使用什么特征
so you can have an
因此 你可以使用一个算法
algorithm look at the data
观察给出的数据
and automatically choose for you
并自动为你选择
whether you want to fit a
到底应该选择
quadratic function, or a cubic function, or something else.
一个二次函数 或者一个三次函数 还是别的函数
But, until we get to
但是 在我们
those algorithms now I just
学到那种算法之前
want you to be aware that
现在我希望你知道
you have a choice in
你需要选择
what features to use, and
使用什么特征
by designing different features
并且通过设计不同的特征
you can fit more complex functions
你能够用更复杂的函数
your data then just fitting a
去拟合你的数据 而不是只用
straight line to the data and
一条直线去拟合
in particular you can put polynomial
特别是 你也可以使用多项式
functions as well and sometimes
函数 有时候
by appropriate insight into the
通过采取适当的角度来观察
feature simply get a much
特征就可以
better model for your data.
得到一个更符合你的数据的模型